Guide to the William S. Glass financial papers, 1852-1867 MS 322
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
William S. Glass financial papers
1852-1867
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Glass, William S.
MS 322
0.1 Linear Feet (74 items in one folder)
The Glass financial papers are primarily a collection of records and receipts of purchases and land sales gathered during the course of Glass' activities as receiver of revenue during the U.S. Civil War.
Biographical Note
William S. Glass was a receiver of revenue for the Confederate government in the Texas counties of Victoria, Cameron, DeWitt, and Refugio.
Scope and Contents
The Glass financial papers are primarily a collection of records and receipts of purchases and land sales gathered during the course of Glass' activities as receiver of revenue during the U.S. Civil War.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. G.B. Davidson, San Antonio, Texas, March 1953.
Index Terms
Subjects
American Civil War (United States: 1861-1865); Business
Document Types
financial records; receipts (financial records); corrrespondence
- Series I: Financial papers, 22366 (Folder 1)
  - Letter from J.D. Cabler to F. Scranton, June 13, 1852 & Letter from J.W. Kuykindall to F. Scranton, August 10, 1852, 22440
  - Letter from E.A. Cabler to A.J. Cunningham, August 26, 1857, Receipt from J. D. Cabler to F. Scranton June 1, 1852 (copy), Receipt from James W. Kuykendall to F. Scranton, June 1, 1852 (copy), Letter from J.D. Cabler to F. Scranton, December 2, 1852 (copy), Letter from James Knight to F. Scranton, May 23, 1852 (copy), & Letter from Peter MacGnol to F. Scranton, n.d. (copy), 22439
  - Receipt from Logan, Sweet, & Palmer to unknown, April 2, 1861; 22438
  - Receipt from William S. Glass to unknown(C.C. Calhoun Co.), January 4, 1862; 22437
  - List of fees Paid to Confederate States, William S. Glass-Receiver, January 1862; 22436
  - List of Expenses owed to Confederate States, William S. Glass-Receiver, January 1862; 22435
  - Check from William S. Glass to J.R. Jefferson, February 9, 1862; 22434
  - List of Fees paid to Confederate States of America (Western Distruct of Texas), February 1862; 22433
  - Receipt from A. Thomson(?) to William S. Glass, March 3, 1862; 22432
  - Receipt from William S. Glass to C.L. Thurmond, March 3, 1862; 22431
  - Receipt from J. Mooley(?) to William S. Glass, May 1, 1862; 22430
  - List of Expenditures from William S. Glass to C.C. Howerton, ca. May 7, 1862; 22429
  - Receipt from J. Mooley(?) to William S. Glass, May 13, 1862; 22428
  - Receipt from William Garnett Clark to William S. Glass, June 11, 1862; 22427
  - Receipt from J. Stringer to William S. Glass, June 30, 1862; 22426
  - Receipt from George Browns to William S. Glass, June 30, 1862; 22425
  - Receipt from W.O. Green to William S. Glass, June 30, 1862; 22424
  - List of Expenditures from William S. Glass to George W. Browne, June 1862; 22423
  - Receipt from P. Sherry(?) to William S. Glass, July 20, 1862; 22422
  - Receipts from T.J. Coats to William S. Glass, September 8, 1862; 22421
  - Receipt from C.L. Thurmond to Lee Leavitt and A.B. Leavitt by William S. Glass, September 15, 1862; 22420
  - Receipt from C.L. Thurmond to Lee Leavitt and A.B. Leavitt by William S. Glass, September 15, 1862; 22419
  - Receipt from C.L. Thurmond to F. Egan Estate of C. Upson by William S. Glass, September 15, 1862; 22418
  - Receipt from C.L. Thurmond to J.D. Vamidy by William S. Glass, September 15, 1862; 22417
  - Receipt from H. Meyer & Co. to William S. Glass, ca. November 1, 1862; 22416
  - List of Expenditures from William S. Glass to J.R. Jefferson, January 26, 1863; 22415
  - List of Taxes Collected by Confederate States Government by William S. Glass, July 1, 1862-January 27, 1863; 22414
  - Receipt from John T. Miller to William S. Glass, January 28, 1863; 22413
  - Receipt from W. de Yeatt(?)? (Avenue Hotel) to William S. Glass, January 28, 1863; 22412
  - Receipt from G.W. Palmer (C.S.A. Depository) to William S. Glass, January 30, 1863; 22411
  - Receipt from C.L. Thurmond to William S. Glass, February 8, 1863; 22410
  - Receipt from H.C. Crucken(?) to William S. Glass, March 14, 1863; 22409
  - Receipt from C.L. Thurmond to William S. Glass, March 31, 1863; 22408
  - Receipt from James N. Smith(?) To William S. Glass (with duplicate), June 4, 1863; 22407
  - Certificate of Redemption of Real Estate from George J. Durham, June 18, 1863; 22406
  - List of Expenditures from William S. Glass to G.W. Browne, June 18, 1863; 22405
  - Receipt from G.W. Palmer to William S. Glass, June 22, 1863; 22404
  - Receipt from C.L. Thurmond to William S. Glass, February 9, 1864; 22403
  - Receipt from C.L. Thurmond to William S. Glass, February 9, 1864; 22402
  - Receipts from C.L. Thurmond to William S. Glass, February 9, 1964 (3 receipts) & List of Expenditures from William S. Glass to C.L. Thurmond, ca. February 1864, 22401
  - Receipts from C.L. Thurmond to William S. Glass (2 receipts), February 9, 1864; 22400
  - Receipts from C.L. Thurmond to William S. Glass (3 receipts), February 9, 1864; 22399
  - Receipt from George W. Palmer to William S. Glass, March 14, 1864; 22398
  - Receipt from George W. Palmer to William S. Glass, May 18, 1864; 22397
  - Receipt from C.C. Howerton to William S. Glass, May 18, 1864; 22396
  - Receipt from D.M. Staff (C.S. Depository) to William S. Glass, June 30,1864; 22395
  - Receipt from D.M. Staff (C.S. Depository) to William S. Glass, October 7, 1864; 22394
  - Receipt from H.W. Branch to William S. Glass, October 14, 1864; 22393
  - Letter from Thomas J. Devine to William S. Glass, November 23, 1864; 22392
  - Receipt from Joseph Urban to William S. Glass, November 28, 1864; 22391
  - Receipt from unknown (witness – H.S. Gaylord) to William S. Glass, November 28, 1864; 22390
  - Receipt from D.M. Staff to William S. Glass, December 8, 1864; 22389
  - Receipt from F. Holferith(?) To William S. Glass, December 8, 1864; 22388
  - Receipt from S.A. White to William S. Glass, December 10, 1864; 22387
  - Receipt from S.A. White to William S. Glass, December 10, 1864; 22386
  - Receipt from George W. Palmer to William S. Glass, December 20, 1864; 22385
  - Receipt from W.S. Thornton to William S. Glass, December 22, 1864; 22384
  - Receipt from J.H. Atkinson to William S. Glass, January 21, 1865; 22383
  - Receipt from C.L. Thurmond to William S. Glass, February 7, 1865; 22382
  - Receipt from James N. Smith(?) to William S. Glass (with duplicate), March 31, 1865; 22381
  - Receipt from S.A. White to William S. Glass, June 9, 1865; 22380
  - List of Expenditures and Receipts from M.A. Taylor, August 29, 1865; 22379
  - Documentation of Agreement between W.W. Pridgers & James Emerson, June 21, 1866; 22378
  - Letter from J.H. McClanahan to F. Scranton, July 5, 1864; 22377
  - Document Re; Agreement between W.W. Pridgers, James Emerson & F. Scranton, ca. July 1866; 22376
  - Letter from J.H. McClanahan to F. Scranton, August 9, 1866; 22375
  - Letter from J.H. McClanahan to F. Scranton, October 2, 1866; 22374
  - Letter from J.H. McClanahan to F. Scranton, October 15, 1866; 22373
  - Letter from J.H. McClanahan to F. Scranton, December 3, 1866; 22372
  - Letter from unknown to J.H. McClanahan, December 4, 1866; 22371
  - Notes from George Emerson & W.W. Pridgers to F. Scranton, mailed to J.H. McClanahan, December 1867; 22370
  - Receipt from H.S. Crucken(?) To William S. Glass, n.d. (pre-1965); 22369
  - Receipt from C.L. Thurmond to H. Kessler, 22368
  - List of Expenditures from George Woodman, n.d. (pre-1865); 22367